Right now
في هذه الأثناء
there is an aspiring teacher
هناك مدرّسة طموحة
who is working on a 60-page paper
تعمل على مقال من 60 صفحة
based on some age-old education theory
معتمدة على نظرية تعليمية عتيقة
developed by some dead education professor
طورها أستاذ تعليم قضى نحبه
wondering to herself what this task
متسائلة مع نفسها عن علاقة هذه
that she's engaging in
المهمة التي انخرطت فيها
has to do with what she wants to do with her life,
مع ما تريد القيام به في حياتها،
which is be an educator,
وهو أن تصبح مربية،
change lives, and spark magic.
وتغير حياة الناس، وتطلق شرارات ساحرة.
Right now there is an aspiring teacher
في هذه الأثناء هناك مدرس طموح
in a graduate school of education
في مؤسسة للدراسات العليا التعليمية
who is watching a professor babble on and on
يشاهد أستاذا يثرثر دون توقف
about engagement
حول الإشراك
in the most disengaging way possible.
بطريقة أبعد ما تكون عن الإشراك.
Right now
في هذه الأثناء
there's a first-year teacher at home
هناك مدرسة في سنتها الأولى في بيتها
who is pouring through lesson plans
تقلب في خطط الدروس
trying to make sense of standards,
محاولة فهم المعايير،
who is trying to make sense of how to grade students appropriately,
محاولة فهم كيفية تقييم عمل التلاميذ كما يجب،
while at the same time saying to herself
وفي نفس الوقت تقول لنفسها
over and over again,
مرارا وتكرارا
"Don't smile till November,"
"لا تبتسمي حتى يصل نوفمبر،"
because that's what she was taught
لأن ذلك ما تم تلقينها إياه
in her teacher education program.
في برنامج تدريب المدرّسين.
Right now there's a student
في هذه الأثناء، هناك تلميذ
who is coming up with a way
يحاول اختلاق طريقة
to convince his mom or dad
لإقناع والديه
that he's very, very sick
بأنه مريض جدا
and can't make it to school tomorrow.
ولا يستطيع الذهاب إلى المدرسة غدا.
On the other hand, right now
وعلى صعيد آخر، وفي هذه الأثناء
there are amazing educators
هناك مربّون مدهشون
that are sharing information,
يشاركون معلومات،
information that is shared in such a beautiful way
معلومات تتم مشاركتها بشكل في غاية الروعة
that the students are sitting at the edge of their seats
لدرجة أن التلاميذ جالسون على حافة مقاعدهم
just waiting for a bead of sweat
مترقبين سقوط قطرة عرق
to drop off the face of this person
من وجه هذا الشخص
so they can soak up all that knowledge.
حتى يستطيعوا امتصاص كل تلك المعرفة.
Right now there is also a person
في هذه الأثناء هناك كذلك شخص
who has an entire audience rapt with attention,
يشد انتباه جمهوره بالكامل،
a person that is weaving a powerful narrative
شخص ينسج سردا قويا
about a world
حول عالم
that the people who are listening
لم يره أي ممن يستمعون له
have never imagined or seen before,
أو تخيلوه قط،
but if they close their eyes tightly enough,
لكن إن أغلقوا أعينهم بما يكفي،
they can envision that world
يستطيعون تخيل ذلك العالم
because the storytelling is so compelling.
لأن سرد القصة مقنع لتلك الدرجة.
Right now there's a person who can tell an audience
في هذه الأثناء، هناك شخص يمكنه أن يقول لجمهور ما
to put their hands up in the air
أن يرفعوا أيديهم إلى السماء
and they will stay there till he says,
وسيبقون كذلك إلى أن يقول،
"Put them down."
"أنزلوها."
Right now.
في هذه الأثناء.
So people will then say,
سيقول الناس إذن،
"Well, Chris, you describe the guy
"حسنا كريس، أنت تصف شخصا
who is going through some awful training
يمر من تدريب قاس
but you're also describing these powerful educators.
لكنك كذلك تصف هؤلاء المربين الكبار.
If you're thinking about the world of education
إن كنت تفكر في عالم التعليم
or urban education in particular,
أو التعليم الحضري بشكل خاص،
these guys will probably cancel each other out,
فإن هؤلاء الأشخاص سيلغون بعضهم البعض على الأرجح،
and then we'll be okay."
وسنكون على ما يرام."
The reality is, the folks I described
الحقيقة أنه، من قمت بوصفهم
as the master teachers,
كمدرسين خبراء،
the master narrative builders,
كخبراء في بناء السياق السردي،
the master storytellers
كخبراء في رواية القصص
are far removed from classrooms.
هم أبعد ما يكونون عن فصول الدراسة.
The folks who know the skills about how to teach
من لديهم مهارات التدريس
and engage an audience
وإشراك الجمهور
don't even know what teacher certification means.
لا يعرفون ما تعنيه شهادة مدرّس حتى.
They may not even have the degrees
قد لا يتوفرون حتى على الشهادات
to be able to have anything
ليستطيعوا القيام بأي شيء
to call an education.
يمكن تسميته تعليما.
And that to me is sad.
وهذا أمر محزن بالنسبة لي.
It's sad because the people who I described,
إنه محزن لأن الناس الذين وصفتهم،
they were very disinterested in the learning process,
كانوا في قمة اللامبالاة بالعملية التعليمية،
want to be effective teachers,
يريدون أن يصبحوا مدرّسين ناجحين،
but they have no models.
لكن ليست لديهم أية نماذج.
I'm going to paraphrase Mark Twain.
سأعيد صياغة اقتباس لمارك توين.
Mark Twain says that proper preparation,
يقول مارك توين أن الاستعداد المناسب،
or teaching,
أو التدريس،
is so powerful that it can turn bad morals to good,
هو في غاية القوة لدرجة أنه يمكنه تحويل القيم الطالحة إلى قيم صالحة،
it can turn awful practices into powerful ones,
يمكنه تحويل الممارسات الشنيعة إلى ممارسات قوية،
it can change men and transform them
يمكنه أن يغيّر الرجال ويحوّلهم
into angels.
إلى ملائكة.
The folks who I described earlier
الأشخاص الذين وصفتهم سابقا
got proper preparation in teaching,
لديهم الاستعداد المناسب للتدريس،
not in any college or university,
ليس في أي جامعة أو كلية،
but by virtue of just being in the same spaces of those who engage.
ولكن فقط بحكم تواجدهم في نفس الفضاءات التي يتواجد فيها من يشركونهم.
Guess where those places are?
خمنوا أين توجد تلك الأماكن؟
Barber shops,
محلات الحلاقة،
rap concerts, and most importantly,
ومهرجانات الراب، وبشكل أهم،
in the black church.
في كنائس السود.
And I've been framing this idea called Pentecostal pedagogy.
وأنا أشتغل على صياغة فكرة تدعى البيداغوجيا العَنصَرية.
Who here has been to a black church?
من منكم هنا سبق وأن زار كنيسة للسود؟
We got a couple of hands.
أرى بعض الأيدي.
You go to a black church,
تذهب إلى كنيسة للسود،
their preacher starts off
يبدأ الواعظ
and he realizes that he has to engage the audience,
ويدرك أن عليه أن يشرك الجمهور،
so he starts off with this sort of wordplay
وبالتالي يبدأ بهذا النوع من التلاعب بالكلام
in the beginning oftentimes,
في البداية غالبا،
and then he takes a pause,
ثم يتوقف قليلا،
and he says, "Oh my gosh, they're not quite paying attention."
ويقول، "يا إلهي، إنهم ليسوا منتبهين كما يجب."
So he says, "Can I get an amen?"
لهذا يقول، "هل لي بـسماع 'آمين'؟"
Audience: Amen.
الجمهور: آمين.
Chris Emdin: So I can I get an amen?
كريس: إذن فهل لي بـسماع 'آمين'؟
CE: And all of a sudden, everybody's reawoken.
كريس: وفجأة، يكون الجميع قد استيقظ من جديد.
That preacher bangs on the pulpit for attention.
يضرب ذلك الواعظ على المنبر ليحصل على الانتباه.
He drops his voice at a very, very low volume
يخفّض صوته لمستوى جد متدني
when he wants people to key into him,
حين يريد من الناس أن يفهموه،
and those things are the skills that we need
وتلك هي المهارات التي نحتاجها
for the most engaging teachers.
لدى المدرّسين الأكثر إشراكا.
So why does teacher education
إذن، لماذا يعطي تعليم المدرسين
only give you theory and theory
ما هو نظري فقط
and tell you about standards and tell you about
ويخبرك بالمعايير ويخبرك
all of these things that have nothing to do
بكل الأشياء التي لا علاقة لها
with the basic skills, that magic that you need
بالمهارات الأساسية، ذلك السحر الذي تحتاجه
to engage an audience, to engage a student?
لإشراك الجمهور، لإشراك التلميذ؟
So I make the argument that we reframe teacher education,
لذا فإنني أحاجج بأنه يجب أن نعيد صياغة تدريب المدرّسين،
that we could focus on content, and that's fine,
أنه يمكننا التركيز على المحتوى، لا مشكل في ذلك،
and we could focus on theories, and that's fine,
ويمكننا التركيز على النظريات،
but content and theories
لكن المحتوى والنظريات
with the absence of the magic
مع انعدام سحر
of teaching and learning means nothing.
التدريس والتعلم لا معنى لهما.
Now people oftentimes say, "Well, magic is just magic."
عادة ما يقول الأشخاص، "حسنا، السحر هو فقط سحر."
There are teachers who,
هناك مدرّسون لديهم
despite all their challenges, who have those skills,
كل تلك المهارات على الرغم من كل التحديات التي تواجههم،
get into those schools and are able to engage an audience,
يمرون من تلك المدارس ويكونون قادرين على إشراك الجمهور،
and the administrator walks by and says,
وحين يمر المدير قربه يقول،
"Wow, he's so good, I wish all my teachers could be that good."
"واو، إنه جيد، أتمنى لو أن كل المدرسين لدي كانوا بنفس المستوى."
And when they try to describe what that is,
وحين يحاولون وصف ماهية ذلك الشيء،
they just say, "He has that magic."
يقولون فقط، "لديه ذلك السحر."
But I'm here to tell you
لكنني هنا لإخباركم
that magic can be taught.
بأن السحر يمكن أن يلقّن.
Magic can be taught.
السحر يمكن أن يلقّن.
Now, how do you teach it?
فكيف يمكننا تدريسه؟
You teach it by allowing people
تدرّسه بالسماح للناس
to go into those spaces
بالذهاب إلى تلك الفضاءات
where the magic is happening.
حيث يحدث السحر.
If you want to be an aspiring teacher in urban education,
إن كنت تريد أن تصبح مدرسا طموحا في التعليم الحضري،
you've got to leave the confines of that university
فعليك أن تخرج من حدود تلك الجامعة
and go into the hood.
وتذهب للأحياء الشعبية.
You've got to go in there and hang out at the barbershop,
عليك أن تذهب إلى هناك وتقضي الوقت في محل الحلاقة،
you've got to attend that black church,
عليك أن تحضرقداسا في كنيسة للسود،
and you've got to view those folks
وعليك أن ترى أولئك الناس
that have the power to engage
الذين يتوفرون على القدرة على الإشراك
and just take notes on what they do.
وتأخذ ملاحظات حول ما يقومون به.
At our teacher education classes at my university,
في أقسام تدريب المدرسين في جامعتي،
I've started a project where every single student
بدأت مشروعا حيث يقوم كل تلميذ
that comes in there sits and watches rap concerts.
يأتي إلى هناك بالجلوس ومشاهدة مهرجانات للراب.
They watch the way that the rappers move
يشاهدون طريقة تحرك مغنيي الراب
and talk with their hands.
وتحدثهم بأيديهم.
They study the way that he walks proudly across that stage.
يدرسون الطريقة التي يمشي بها متفاخرا على الخشبة.
They listen to his metaphors and analogies,
يستمعون للاستعارات والتشبيهات،
and they start learning these little things
ويبدؤون في تعلم هذه الأشياء الصغيرة
that if they practice enough
والتي إن تدربوا عليها بما يكفي
becomes the key to magic.
تصبح مفتاح السحر.
They learn that if you just stare at a student
يتعلمون أنه إن قمت فقط بالتحديق في تلميذ
and raise your eyebrow about a quarter of an inch,
ورفعت حاجبك بحوالي ربع إنش،
you don't have to say a word
فليس عليك أن تقول كلمة
because they know that that means that you want more.
لأنهم يعرفون أن ذلك يعني أنك تريد أكثر.
And if we could transform teacher education
وإن أمكننا تحويل تدريب المدرسين
to focus on teaching teachers
ليركز على تدريس المدرسين
how to create that magic
كيفية خلق ذلك السحر
then poof! we could make dead classes come alive,
فإننا نستطيع في رمشة عين إحياء الفصول الدراسية،
we could reignite imaginations,
سيمكننا إعادة إشعال المخيلات،
and we can change education.
وتغيير التعليم.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)